<Chapter Label="Introduction"><Heading>Introduction</Heading>

<Section Label="Aims"><Heading>General aims</Heading>

The overall aim of <Package>QPA</Package> is to provide computational
tools in basic research in mathematics (algebra). It seeks to furnish
users within and outside the area of representation theory of finite
dimensional algebras with a computational software package that will
help in exploring a problem and testing conjectures. As with all
software development, new ideas and question will arise. The ability
to study and compute examples will help in proving or disproving
well-established questions/conjectures.  Furthermore, it will enable
us to consider new examples which were not accessible by hand or other
means before. In this way, we hope that <Package>QPA</Package> will
aid in the development, not only of the area of representation theory
of finite dimensional algebras, but also of a broad variety of other
areas of mathematics, where such structures occur. In addition we
aspire to create a research environment for international cooperation
on computational representation theory of finite dimensional algebras.
</Section> 

<Section Label="Installation"><Heading>Installation and system requirements</Heading>

<Package>QPA</Package> does not use external binaries and, therefore,
works without restrictions on the type of the operating system. This
version of the package is designed for GAP >= 4.5 and no
compatibility with previous releases of GAP 4 is guaranteed. However,
<Package>QPA</Package> depend on the Groebner basis GAP-package
<Package>GBNP</Package>.<P/>

To use the <Package>QPA</Package> online help it is necessary to
install the GAP 4 package <Package>GAPDoc</Package> by Frank Lübeck
and Max Neunhöffer, which is available from the GAP site or from
<URL>http://www.math.rwth-aachen.de/~Frank.Luebeck/GAPDoc/</URL>.<P/>  

<Package>QPA</Package> is distributed in standard format (tar.gz)
and can be obtained from
<URL>http://www.math.ntnu.no/~oyvinso/QPA/</URL>.  To
install the package, unpack its archive in the pkg subdirectory of
your GAP installation. In a similar way install the GAP-package
<Package>GBNP</Package> which is available from the GAP site.<P/>

For more detailed installation information and an alternative way for
downloading <Package>QPA</Package> see
<URL>http://www.math.ntnu.no/~oyvinso/QPA/</URL>.<P/>

</Section>
</Chapter>
